[
  {
    "question": "Identify the deployment model among the following.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are deployment models.",
    "options": [
      "Private",
      "Public",
      "Hybrid",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose among the following which is related to services provided by the cloud.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Sourcing is related to services provided by the cloud.",
    "options": [
      "Reliability",
      "Souring",
      "Ownership",
      "AaaS"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the correct IaaS provider among the following.",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) EC2 is the IaaS service provider.",
    "options": [
      "EC2",
      "EC1",
      "EC10",
      "Hybrid"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the components which are known as a hypervisor.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) VMM is known as the hypervisor.",
    "options": [
      "VMC",
      "VMM",
      "VC",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the correct relationship of cloud services to customers.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Cloud services are one-to-many relationships with their customers.",
    "options": [
      "One-One",
      "One-Many",
      "Many-one",
      "Many-Many"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following refers to network or internet?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Cloud computing refers to network or internet.",
    "options": [
      "Cloud",
      "CRM",
      "Cloud computing",
      "Computing"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term “elasticity” in cloud computing refer to?",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) Elasticity means the ability to scale down or scale-up.",
    "options": [
      "Ability to scale down",
      "Parallel",
      "Ability to scale up",
      "Both a and c are correct"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of IaaS cloud computing",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are examples of IaaS cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      "Linode",
      "Cisco meta cloud",
      "Digital ocean",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of SaaS cloud computing.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are examples of SaaS cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      "Dropbox",
      "Salesforce",
      "Google workshop",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following, which are examples of PaaS cloud computing",
    "options": [
      {
        "content": "Heroku",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "A"
      },
      {
        "content": "Google App Engine",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "B"
      },
      {
        "content": "AWS Elastic Beanstalk",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "C"
      },
      {
        "content": "All of the above",
        "checked": true,
        "explain": "All of the above are examples of PaaS cloud computing.",
        "code": "D"
      }
    ],
    "done": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose among the following, which are the characteristics of IaaS.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) All of the above are characteristics of IaaS.",
    "options": [
      "Highly scalable",
      "Flexible and dynamic platform",
      "Facilitates hardware access to many users",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "In cloud computing, the client is on which end.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Client is on the front end.",
    "options": [
      "Backend",
      "Frontend",
      "Depends",
      "Both a and b"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year was Google Compute Engine released?",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) Google Compute Engine was released in 2012.",
    "options": [
      "2012",
      "2009",
      "2015",
      "2006"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most important concern of cloud computing?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Security is the most important concern of cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      "Cost",
      "Space",
      "Security",
      "Platform"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Total types of cloud computing services are?",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) There are a total of 4 cloud computing services - public, private, hybrid, multi-clouds.",
    "options": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "PaaS stands for?",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) PaaS stands for Platform as a service.",
    "options": [
      "Platform as a service",
      "Platform as a software",
      "Parallel as a service",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The term “hybrid cloud” refers to?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Hybrid cloud refers to the combination of private and public cloud.",
    "options": [
      "Private cloud",
      "Public cloud",
      "Combination of private and public cloud",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the technique used for creating cloud computing.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Virtualization is the technique used for creating cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      "Insubordination",
      "Cannibalization",
      "Virtualization",
      "Transubstantiation"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Total steps of deployment stage in cloud computing are?",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) The total deployment stage in cloud computing is 4.",
    "options": [
      "3",
      "4",
      "5",
      "6"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following, which provides a runtime environment.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) PaaS provides a runtime environment for applications.",
    "options": [
      "IaaS",
      "SaaS",
      "PaaS",
      "XaaS"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "SAN stands for ______",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) SAN stands for Storage area network.",
    "options": [
      "Storage area network",
      "Security area network",
      "Switch application network",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the most basic level of storage.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) DAS is the most basic level of storage.",
    "options": [
      "NAS",
      "SAN",
      "DAS",
      "ISCSI"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the storage technologies among the following which have the best performance.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) SAN has the best performance among all others.",
    "options": [
      "NAS",
      "SAN",
      "DAS",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following layers, which are not related to SAN architecture.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) Object layer is not related to SAN architecture.",
    "options": [
      "Storage layer",
      "Host layer",
      "Fabric layer",
      "Object layer"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following, which provides the GUI for interaction with the cloud.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Client infrastructure provides the GUI for interaction with the cloud.",
    "options": [
      "Server",
      "Client",
      "Client infrastructure",
      "Application"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose among the following options, on which utility computing is based.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) Utility computing is based on SOA.",
    "options": [
      "Virtual isolation model",
      "Grid Computing model",
      "Pay-per use model",
      "SOA"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "On what is cloud computing-based.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Cloud computing is based on virtualization.",
    "options": [
      "Modulation",
      "Hybridization",
      "Virtualization",
      "Multiplexing"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a cloud?",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) Hadoop can be considered as a cloud.",
    "options": [
      "Hadoop",
      "Web applications",
      "Intranet",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "SaaS stands for?",
    "options": [
      {
        "content": "Scalability as a service",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "A"
      },
      {
        "content": "Software as a service",
        "checked": true,
        "explain": "SaaS stands for Software as a service.",
        "code": "B"
      },
      {
        "content": "Service as a software",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "C"
      },
      {
        "content": "None",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "D"
      }
    ],
    "done": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Total types of hypervisors are?",
    "options": [
      {
        "content": "2",
        "checked": true,
        "explain": "There are two types of hypervisors.",
        "code": "A"
      },
      {
        "content": "3",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "B"
      },
      {
        "content": "4",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "C"
      },
      {
        "content": "5",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "D"
      }
    ],
    "done": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Total types of PaaS are?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) There are four types of hypervisors.",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "3",
      "4",
      "5a"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "QPS stands for?",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) QPS stands for Query per second.",
    "options": [
      "Query period sites",
      "Quantum per second",
      "Quality Per Service",
      "Query per second"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the most important use of cloud computing.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Data storage is the most important use of cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      "Data privacy",
      "Data storage",
      "Cost-effective",
      "Security"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a cloud platform by amazon?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) Amazon provided AWS cloud service.",
    "options": [
      "Cloudera",
      "Azure",
      "AWS",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following, which monitors the performance of major cloud-based services in real-time.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) CloudSensor monitors the performance of major cloud-based services in real-time.",
    "options": [
      "CloudMetrices",
      "CloudSensor",
      "CloudWatch",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "GAE stands for?",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) GAE stands for Google apps engine.",
    "options": [
      "Google apps engine",
      "Google applied to engineer",
      "Google architecture engineering",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the most restrictive and most refined cloud service model.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) PaaS is the most restrictive and most refined cloud service model.",
    "options": [
      "IaaS",
      "XaaS",
      "SaaS",
      "PaaS"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following terms refers to the management and location of cloud infrastructure.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Deployment refers to the management and location of cloud infrastructure.",
    "options": [
      "Application",
      "Deployment",
      "Service",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the types of dimensions in Cloud Cube?",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) There are 4 types of dimensions in Cloud Cube.",
    "options": [
      "2",
      "3",
      "4",
      "5"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "IaaS stands for?",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) IaaS stands for Infrastructure as a service",
    "options": [
      "Information as a service",
      "Infrastructure as a service",
      "Infrastructure as a software",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the highest degree of integration of cloud computing.",
    "options": [
      {
        "content": "SaaS",
        "checked": true,
        "explain": "SaaS is the highest degree of integration of cloud computing.",
        "code": "A"
      },
      {
        "content": "PaaS",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "B"
      },
      {
        "content": "IaaS",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "C"
      },
      {
        "content": "CaaS",
        "checked": false,
        "explain": null,
        "code": "D"
      }
    ],
    "done": true
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose among the following which allows the different OS to run in their memory space.",
    "answer": "Answer:  C) VMM allows the different OS to run in their memory space.",
    "options": [
      "VMS",
      "VMS",
      "VMM",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the VM monitor and CPU emulator among the following.",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) QEMU is the VM monitor and CPU emulator.",
    "options": [
      "Parallels",
      "QEMU",
      "VMS",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the Type 1 hypervisor among the following.",
    "answer": "Answer:  D) KVM is the Type 1 hypervisor.",
    "options": [
      "KVM",
      "Virtual Server 2005 R2",
      "Wind River Simics",
      "KVM"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "IT Architecture Development comes under which of the following phases.",
    "answer": "Answer:  A) IT Architecture Development under planning phase.",
    "options": [
      "Planning phase",
      "Development phase",
      "Strategy phase",
      "Testing phase"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Total types of cloud architecture are?",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) There is a total of two types of cloud architecture - frontend and backend.",
    "options": [
      "1",
      "2",
      "3",
      "4"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "By whom is the backend used primarily?",
    "answer": "Answer:  B) Backend is used primarily by Service providers.",
    "options": [
      "User",
      "Service provider",
      "Client",
      "Stockholders"
    ],
    "done": false
  }
]